{
  "title": "la comida 2024",
  "cards": [
    { "front": "el desayuno", "back": "breakfast" },
    { "front": "el almuerzo", "back": "lunch" },
    { "front": "la cena", "back": "dinner" },
    { "front": "el agua", "back": "water" },
    { "front": "la leche", "back": "milk" },
    { "front": "el café", "back": "coffee" },
    { "front": "el jugo", "back": "juice" },
    { "front": "el refresco", "back": "soda" },
    { "front": "la limonada", "back": "lemonade" },
    { "front": "el aguacate", "back": "avocado" },
    { "front": "la cebolla", "back": "onion" },
    { "front": "el maíz/el elote", "back": "corn" },
    { "front": "el arroz", "back": "rice" },
    { "front": "los frijoles", "back": "beans" },
    { "front": "la papa", "back": "potato" },
    { "front": "la lechuga", "back": "lettuce" },
    { "front": "el tomate", "back": "tomato" },
    { "front": "la zanahoria", "back": "carrot" },
    { "front": "las fresas", "back": "strawberries" },
    { "front": "el limón", "back": "lemon/lime" },
    { "front": "la manzana", "back": "apple" },
    { "front": "la naranja", "back": "orange" },
    { "front": "el melón", "back": "cantaloupe" },
    { "front": "los arándanos", "back": "blueberries" },
    { "front": "los plátanos/las bananas", "back": "bananas" },
    { "front": "la piña", "back": "pineapple" },
    { "front": "la sandía", "back": "watermelon" },
    { "front": "el bistec", "back": "steak" },
    { "front": "la carne de res", "back": "beef" },
    { "front": "el cerdo", "back": "pork" },
    { "front": "el jamón", "back": "ham" },
    { "front": "el pollo", "back": "chicken" },
    { "front": "el pescado", "back": "fish (food)" },
    { "front": "los camarones", "back": "shrimp" },
    { "front": "los huevos", "back": "eggs" },
    { "front": "el atún", "back": "tuna" },
    { "front": "el pavo", "back": "turkey" },
    { "front": "el tocino", "back": "bacon" },
    { "front": "el pan", "back": "bread" },
    { "front": "la pera", "back": "pear" },
    { "front": "la espinaca", "back": "spinach" },
    { "front": "el té", "back": "tea" },
    { "front": "el queso", "back": "cheese" },
    { "front": "la crema", "back": "cream" },
    { "front": "el aceite", "back": "oil" },
    { "front": "la mantequilla", "back": "butter" },
    { "front": "el tazón", "back": "bowl" },
    { "front": "el plato", "back": "plate" },
    { "front": "el vaso", "back": "cup" },
    { "front": "la taza", "back": "mug" },
    { "front": "el cuchillo", "back": "knife" },
    { "front": "la cuchara", "back": "spoon" },
    { "front": "el tenedor", "back": "fork" },
    { "front": "el sartén", "back": "pan" },
    { "front": "la olla", "back": "pot" },
    { "front": "el cucharón", "back": "ladle" },
    { "front": "la licuadora", "back": "blender" },
    { "front": "la tostadora", "back": "toaster" },
    { "front": "el pelador", "back": "peeler" },
    { "front": "el rallador", "back": "grater" }
  ]
}
